Inventory of the Alexandra Andreevna Voronine Yourieff Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs and negatives, undated (Folder 38: 4-5)
- Writings--Quisling book. Correspondence--W. George and Alexandra Yourieff, 1979-1983. (Box-folder 39: 1)
  Includes Alexandra's letters regarding Quisling estate and probate
- Original certified copy of the durable power of attorney made and given by Alexandra Yourieff to her husband W. George Yourieff, 1989 March 6 (Folder 39: 2)
- Notes, 1957, 1987-1988(?). (Folder 39: 3)
  Includes a letter
- Family correspondence, 1949-1997. (Folder 39: 4)
  Includes poetry, copies of official confidential letters
- W. George Yourieff--Correspondence
  - 1946, 1976 (Folder 39: 5)
  - 1961 (Folder 39: 6)
- Eugene--Correspondence, 1949-1962 (Folder 39: 7)
- Alexandra Yourieff--Copies of her artwork, 1974 (Folder 39: 8-9)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 39: 10)
- Photocopies, undated (Folder 39: 11)
- Miscellany, 1997, undated (Folder 39: 12)
- Framed portrait of Tatarinov, undated (Box-folder 40: 1)
- Article in Palo Alto Daily on Alexandra Yourieff, 1976 September 6. (Folder 40: 2)
  Depicts some of her new artwork
- Correspondence, 1923-1931 (Folder 40: 3)
- Photograph and child's drawing, undated (Folder 40: 4)
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 40: 5)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company (Box 41)
  - By-laws and minutes of meetings of board of directors, 1957-1965, 1976 (Folder 41: 1)
  - Minutes of meetings of board of directors, 1966-1977 (Folder 41: 2)
- Shklovskii, Viktor, Zoo ili pis'ma ne o liubvi, Berlin, 1923. (Folder 41: 3)
  Printed copy
- Sandra (Aleksandra) Yourieff, El Palo Alto Art Show winner, 1971. (Folder 41: 4)
  Flyer and articles
- Lease agreement on Tsingtao property, 1951 December 5 (Folder 41: 5)
- Correspondence
  - Scardina Builders, Inc., San Jose, California, 1970 (Folder 41: 6)
  - General, 1948, 1962 (Folder 41: 7)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1970-1974 (Folder 41: 8)
- Photographs and negatives, 1937-1973 (Folder 41: 9)
- Yourieff family official documents, 1915-1949 (Box-folder 42: 1)
- Transcript of unidentified interview, undated (Folder 42: 2)
- Family correspondence, 1949-1976 (Folder 42: 3)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Diaries
    - Undated (Folder 42: 4)
      unidentified
    - 1922-1932 (Folder 42: 5)
      (France)
  - Business-related material, 1937-1973 (Folder 42: 6)
- Writings--Quisling book (Box 43)
  - "Quisling," part #2 and #3, undated.
    VHS videocassette
  - "Alexandra Voronine," part #2, 1986 November 23 and 1987 December 20.
- Holograph, 1933 (Folder 43: 1)
- Notebook
  - Unidentified, undated (Folder 43: 2)
  - Russian romances, unidentified, undated (Folder 43: 3)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Day books labeled as "Diaries"
    - 1983-1985 (Folder 43: 4)
    - 1985-1986 (Folder 43: 5)
  - Business-related material
    - undated (Folder 43: 6)
    - 1967 (Folder 43: 7)
- J. Hunter, Inc.--Article of incorporation, 1959 December 30, and minutes of meeting of board of directors, 1960 January 13 (Box-folder 44: 1)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Business-related financial documents, 1973 (Folder 44: 2)
  - Eighteen-unit condominium apartment project, 1973. (Folder 44: 3)
    Proposal and contract
- Tenants correspondence, 1958-1970 (Folder 44: 4)
- Correspondence, 1948 (Folder 44: 5)
- Writings--Quisling book. My Husband Vidkun Quisling, section F, undated (Box-folder 45: 1)
- "Alexandra and [W.] George Yourieff important documents" (as written on the envelope), 1944-1945 (Folder 45: 2)
- Alexandra and W. George Yourieff--Financial documents--Art and design studio and real estate office, 1973 (Folder 45: 3)
- Writings--Quisling book. My Husband Vidkun Quisling, by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, section H., undated. (Folder 45: 4)
- Writing draft, unidentified, 1968(?) (Folder 45: 5)
- Correspondence (China), 1949 (Folder 45: 6)
- Northern Star of China Lodge, 1949-1984. (Folder 45: 7)
  Includes photographs and Life magazine issue, 1956 October
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related documents
  - General, 1971-1974 (Folder 45: 8)
  - Article of incorporation, 1957 February 15 (Folder 45: 9)
  - Liquidation, 1976-1977 (Folder 45: 10)
- Letters to Mara Pasechnikova from her mother, 1931-1942 (Folder 45: 11)
- Correspondence
  - General, 1977 (Folder 45: 12)
  - Ketie Lund, attorney, Norway, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 1)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - My Husband Vidlun Quisling, by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, synopsis, three sections, undated (Folder 46: 2)
  - In Quisling's Shadow, draft, 1980(?) (Folder 46: 3)
- Correspondence--Dahl-Hansen, 1980-1981 (Folder 46: 4)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Correspondence--Alexandra Voronine Yourieff and Christiania Bank og Kreditkasse, Norway, 1984-1985; Quisling the Unknown by Unwanted Witness, 1978? (Folder 46: 5)
    Includes copyright agreement
  - Transcripts of tapes by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, 1975. (Folder 46: 6)
- Miscellaneous financial material, 1972-1975 (Folder 46: 7)
- Correspondence, 1930-1990. (Box-folder 47: 1)
  Includes essay "The Opera Singer," by Kirsten A. Seaver, undated. Printed copy
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Photographs of the art objects in Quisling home in Oslo, Norway, undated (Folder 47: 2)
  - My Husband Vidkun Quisling, synopsis, 1972(?). (Folder 47: 3)
    Includes review by Kirsten A. Seaver, 1986
  - My Husband Vidkun Quisling, synopsis. (Folder 47: 4)
    Includes copy of contract
  - Articles on Vidkun Quisling, in English and Norwegian, 1980, and correspondence, 1975-1980 (Folder 47: 5)
  - Correspondence--Paul M. Hayes, 1973-1985 (Folder 47: 6)
  - Newly found Vidkun Quisling private archives, 1984-1985. (Folder 47: 7)
    Includes list of Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff possessions, in Norwegian
  - List of corrections and notes on Lars Torekull's three articles for Alle Kvinner entitled "Alexandra Quisling,", 1981 (Folder 47: 8)
  - Correspondence--Scott Meredith (Scott Meredith Literary Agency, Inc.) regarding book on Quisling, 1978-1979 (Folder 47: 9)
  - Alexandra Voronine-Quisling-Yourieff, first draft of the English translation (from Russian?), 1980(?) (Folder 47: 10)
- Family correspondence--Arsene, 1937-1960 (Box-folder 48: 1)
- Alexandra Yourieff--Correspondence, 1952-1957 (Folder 48: 2)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Correspondence and court documents with Oslo municipal court, Norway, 1984-1985 (Folder 48: 3)
  - Alexandra and W. George Yourieff with Kirsten A. Seaver, 1987. (Folder 48: 4-5)
    Includes draft of a few chapters of Quisling book
  - Correspondence, 1988; draft of chapter 18-24 of Quisling book, undated (Folder 48: 6)
  - Copies from Norwegian magazines about Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff, 1975, 1978; Correspondence--Suzanne Palme Literary Agency, Oslo, Norway, 1980-1981 (Folder 48: 7)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1972-1973 (Folder 48: 8)
- Writings--Quisling book. Den Ukjente fru Quisling, series of articles in Norwegian magazines, 1975, 1988 (Box-folder 49: 1)
- Certified copy of the original trust agreement and original wills, 1989 August 16 (Folder 49: 2)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Draft of a new will, 1996 (Folder 49: 3)
  - Drafts of correspondence (mostly with Gladis), undated (Folder 49: 4)
- Writings--Quisling book. Notes on Quisling, Kirsten A Seaver, Indiana University Press, 1972 (Folder 49: 5)
- Documented cash loss, drafts of letters, 1982(?) (Folder 49: 6)
- W. George Yourieff--Diary, 1930-1961 (Folder 49: 7)
  (goes backwards - with memorable events that took place many years ago)
- Writings--Quisling book. (Folder 49: 8)
  Transcripts of tapes by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, book #4 (continuation on tape #12). In Russian
- W. George Yourieff--Personal data, 1951 (Folder 49: 9)
- Correspondence, 1988 (Folder 49: 10)
- Minutes of first meeting of directors, 1967 August 25 (Folder 49: 11)
- W. George Yourief--Business-related material, 1969-1974 (Folder 49: 12-13)
- Miscellany, 1958, 1973 (Folder 49: 14)
- Framed watercolor image, undated (Box-folder 50: 1)
- Address book, undated (Folder 50: 2)
- One man show of Sandra (Alexandra) Yourieff, Palo Alto Art Club, 1970 March-May (Folder 50: 3)
- Writing draft, unidentified, undated (Folder 50: 4)
- Clippings, 1969, 1974 (Folder 50: 5)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Business-related material, 1968-1970 (Folder 50: 6-7)
  - Zakony Yur'eva i priblizhaiushchisia konets istorii, draft and typescript, undated (Folder 50: 8)
  - Diary, Tsingtao, undated (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Diary, 1961 (Folder 51: 2)
- Writing drafts, 1988 (Folder 51: 3)
- Correspondence, 1949-1970 (Folder 51: 4)
- Clippings, printed matter (Folder 51: 5)
- Notes, undated (Folder 51: 6)
- Miscellany, 1974-1976 (Folder 51: 7)
- W. George Yourieff (Box 52)
  - Draft of will and trust, undated (Folder 52: 1)
  - Writings
    - The Chinese: Portrait of a People
      - Early drafts, 1968. (Folder 52: 2)
        Mostly in Russian
      - Early drafts, undated. (Folder 52: 3)
      - Latest copy, undated. (Folder 52: 4)
    - Essay on Russia (draft), undated (Folder 52: 5)
- Notes, undated (Folder 52: 6)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 52: 7)
  - Business-related material, 1952-1969 (Folder 52: 8)
- Clippings, 1970-1971 (Folder 52: 9)
- W. George Yourief--Business-related material, 1952-1983 (Folder 52: 10-11)
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 52: 12)
- Family photographs, undated (Box-folder 53: 1)
- Antonina A. Yourieff--Personal documents, 1946-1956. (Folder 53: 2)
- Writings
  - "Evil," essay, undated. (Folder 53: 3)
  - Essay, unidentified, undated. (Folder 53: 4)
  - Essay on Russia, 1933. (Folder 53: 5)
  - Essay on Russia, undated. (Folder 53: 6)
- Family correspondence, 1953-1957 (Folder 53: 7)
- Photographs, Shanghai, undated (Folder 53: 8)
- Notebook, 1949 (Folder 53: 9)
  (Day book)
- Miscellany, 1949-1956, 1995 (Folder 53: 10)
- Correspondence, 1970-1978. (Box-folder 54: 1-2)
- Photo album, 1925 (Folder 54: 3)
- Miscellany, 1949, undated (Folder 54: 4)
- Family correspondence, 1949-1973 (Box-folder 55: 1)
- Correspondence
  - Arsik, 1973 (Folder 55: 2)
  - General, 1979-1982 (Folder 55: 3)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Notes for his will, 1993 (Folder 55: 4)
  - Codicil to last will and testament, 1970 August 27 (Folder 55: 5)
- Drafts of writing about China and the Chinese, undated (Folder 55: 6)
- Writings, translations, 1927-1930 (Folder 55: 7)
- Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States--Correspondence and official documents, 1970. (Folder 55: 8)
  Includes final decision in the matter of the claim of W. George and Alexandra Yourieff
- W. George Yourieff--Notes, undated (Folder 55: 9)
- Alexandra Yourieff--Photographs, 1930 (Folder 55: 10)
  (China)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company
  - Real estate contract, 1975 (Folder 55: 11)
  - Lease agreement, 1980 (Folder 55: 12)
- Vasiliev, A. A., The 60th In the Crimea, copy of his book, 1936 (Folder 55: 13-14)
- Family correspondence, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 56: 1)
- W. George Yourieff--Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Folder 56: 2)
- Letters from Yura, 1956-1962 (Folder 56: 3)
- Writings--Quisling book. Correspondence with different Norwegian authorities regarding Alexandra's publications, 1973-1980. (Folder 56: 4)
  Includes her articles published in Alle Kviner. Also includes agreement between Alle Kvinner (a Norwegian magazine in Oslo), Lars Torekull (a reporter and a U.S. correspondent), and Alexandra Voronine (Quisling), 1975 July
- Norwegian Star of China Lodge, China, Tsingtao, 1933-1949. (Folder 56: 5)
  Mostly correspondence
- Correspondence (Box 57)
  - The Bonnier Magazine Group, 1975 (Folder 57: 1)
  - General
    - 1929-1993 (Folder 57: 2)
    - 1978-1993. (Folder 57: 3)
      Mostly greeting cards
- Blank cards depicting Frida Kahlo, undated (Folder 57: 4)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 57: 5-7)
- Miscellany, 1963-1992 (Folder 57: 8-9)
- W. George Yourieff--Day books (Box 58)
  - 1975, 1988, undated (Folder 58: 1)
  - 1955, 1957 (Folder 58: 2)
- Correspondence, notes, undated (Folder 58: 3)
- My Story Book (child's short stories), unidentified, undated (Folder 58: 4)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 58: 5-6)
- Miscellany, 1980-1993 (Folder 58: 7)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 59: 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1940-1992 (Folder 59: 5)
- Writings--Quisling book. Alexandra Voronine--Biographical chronology (unapproved) by Kirsten Seaver, 1986 January. (Folder 59: 6)
- Newspaper WestArt (West Art), 1965-1966 (Folder 59: 7)
  (three issues)
- Verses, unidentified, undated (Folder 59: 8)
- Miscellany, 1964, undated (Folder 59: 9)
- Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 60: 1)
- Personal notes, undated (Folder 60: 2)
- Lyrics, undated (Folder 60: 3)
- Writing, unidentified, undated (Folder 60: 4)
- Magazine/newspaper articles, 1989-1992 (Folder 60: 5)
- Art exhibit advertisements, 1990s (Folder 60: 6)
- Financial documents, 1990, undated (Folder 60: 7)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 60: 8-9)
- Miscellany, 1949, undated (Folder 60: 10)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 61: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1956-1985 (Folder 61: 4)
- W. George Yourieff--Holograph of essay, 1966-1967 (Folder 61: 5)
- Book of sayings, unidentified, undated (Folder 61: 6)
- Notebook, unidentified, undated (Folder 61: 7)
- Printed matter--Brochure on exhibit of Society of Western Artists, M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, San Francisco, 1971 (Folder 61: 8)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1960, undated (Folder 61: 9)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 62: 1)
- Correspondence
  - General
    - 1975 (Folder 62: 2)
    - 1975-1976 (Folder 62: 3)
    - 1977 (Folder 62: 4)
  - Hoover Institution (and other organizations), 1970-1971 (Folder 62: 5)
- Notes
  - Svetlana, undated (Folder 62: 6)
  - America (USA), 1967(?) (Folder 62: 7)
  - Tatarinoff, undated (Folder 62: 8)
  - Makhno, Nestor--Letters discussing memories of him, 1968 (Folder 62: 9)
  - Russia, undated (Folder 62: 10)
  - Religion (Russia, China, America)--Essays and notes, 1966(?) (Folder 62: 11)
- W. George Yourieff--Autobiography, undated (Folder 62: 12)
- Essay "Church,", undated. (Folder 62: 13)
  Printed copy. In Russian
- Historical documents on Vidkun Quisling (property of Mr. and Mrs. W. George Yourieff), undated. (Box-folder 63: 1)
  Includes copy of letters between Vidkun Quisling and Alexandra, 1923, 1925
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, undated (Folder 63: 2)
- Notes, 1965, 1977 (Folder 63: 3-4)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 63: 5-7)
- Writings--Quisling book. In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver (latest corrected version), 1985 May (Box-folder 64: 1-2)
- Two paintings in frame, undated (Folder 64: 3)
- Publishers Weekly magazine, 1985 August 2 (Folder 64: 4)
- Postcards, undated (Folder 64: 5)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1950 (Folder 64: 6)
- Family correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 65: 1)
- State Compensation Insurance Fund, California, 1977-1982 (Folder 65: 2)
- Yourieff, Mr. and Mrs., very personal financial matter. (Folder 65: 3-4)
  Includes letter to be opened in case of death or prolonged disability, 1971 December 16
- Photographs, undated (Folder 65: 5)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company--Financial report (Box 66)
  - 1963-1965 (Folder 66: 1)
  - 1966-1969 (Folder 66: 2)
- Card catalog with sayings, notes, undated (Folder 66: 3-4)
- Miscellany, 1977 (Folder 66: 5)
- W. George Yourieff--Notes for articles and books, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 67: 1)
- Notes, undated (Folder 67: 2)
- Magazine articles, 1972-1974 (Folder 67: 3)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company--Financial report
  - 1957-1959 (Folder 67: 4)
  - 1960-1962 (Folder 67: 5)
  - 1969-1971 (Folder 67: 6)
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 67: 7)
- Important personal financial documents, 1977 (Box-folder 68: 1)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related documents, 1967 (Folder 68: 2)
- Yourieff family tree, undated (Folder 68: 3)
- Clippings, undated (Folder 68: 4)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver, first two chapters, 1988 (Folder 68: 5)
  - "The Unknown Mrs. Quisling," by Lars Torekull, Alle Kvinner, Oslo, Norway, 1975 (Folder 68: 6-7)
  - Copies of Alle Kvinner magazine with articles on Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff, 1975 (Folder 68: 8)
- Notes, miscellany, 1968, undated (Folder 68: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book (Box 69)
  - The Private Quisling and His Two Women, by Arve Juritzen (translated by Kirsten A. Seaver), 1988 (Folder 69: 1)
  - In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver, undated
    - Volume 1, part A (Folder 69: 2)
    - Volume 1, part B (Folder 69: 3-4)
  - Important historical documents--First original English manuscript on Vidkun Quisling by his first wife Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, undated (Box-folder 70: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1923-1979 (Folder 70: 4)
- History of Yourieff family, undated. (Folder 70: 5)
- Antonina A. Yourieff (mother)--Visa, 1951-1955 (Folder 70: 6)
- W. George Yourieff--Notes, undated (Folder 70: 7)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company, undated (Folder 70: 8)
- Article from Ogonek magazine, 1973 March. (Folder 70: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book (Box 71)
  - In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver
    - Basic 27 chapters, undated (Folder 71: 1)
    - 1987 version (Folder 71: 2)
  - Question to the plaintiff Alexandra Voronine Yourieff. Translated from Norwegian, undated. (Folder 71: 3)
  - In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver, undated (Box-folder 72: 1)
  - Copies of Alle Kvinner magazine with articles on Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff, 1975 (Folder 72: 2)
  - Various documents concerning Maria Pasechnikova (Quisling) (Box 73)
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 73: 1)
    - 1983 (Folder 73: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1994, mostly with Norwegian publishers. (Folder 73: 3)
    Includes verdict of Oslo Municipal Court, 1986 December 16; and draft of a new copyright agreement, 1994 May 15
- Correspondence
  - General
    - 1972-1973 (Folder 73: 4)
    - 1943-1981. (Folder 73: 5)
      Includes two drafts of writings, typescripts
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Correspondence regarding Arve Juritzen's The Private Quisling and His Two Women, 1986-1987. (Folder 73: 6)
    Includes two typescripts of the manuscript. Also includes copies of letters written by Maria Quisling and Vidkun Quisling, now in the University of Oslo library manuscript collection (translated by Kirsten A. Seaver in September of 1987)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982. (Folder 73: 7)
    Includes a number of newspaper clippings and translations concerning the Arve Juritzen's book, 1988
  - Correspondence between Alexandra and W. George Yourieff, Kirsten A. Seaver, and Arve Juritzen, 1986-1987. (Folder 73: 8)
    Includes information about the informal, off the record conversation of Alexandra Voronine with Stein Ørnhøi (of Norway's Rettsaken TV), 1986 November 19. Includes also photographs and photocopies of treasures from the Quisling home
- Letter of W. George Yourieff to the United States embassy in Oslo, 1980 August 24 (Folder 73: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Correspondence, translation, 1924, 1980-1983. (Folder 73: 10)
    Includes first draft of the preliminary claim by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, the plaintiff, for presentation to the municipal court of Oslo, 1983 July. Also includes letter of Vidkun Quisling to his parents discussing his two women (Alexandra and Maria), 1924 January 24
  - Correspondence and miscellany, 1980-1992. (Folder 73: 11)
    Includes letter from the Quisling Archives at the University of Oslo library; notes on Arnold Ræstad's unpublished manuscript, The Case Quisling, 1961; notes on Benjamin Vogt, Mennesket Vidkun og forræderen Quisling (The person Vidkun and the traitor Quisling), Aschehoug, Oslo, 1965; notes on cultural debate between Hans Frederik Dahl and Kirsten A. Seaver, Aftenposten, 1992 February; agreement between Alexandra and W. George Yourieff and Kirsten Seaver regarding translation of Alexandra Yourieff's book about Vidkun Quisling, 1981 July 22
  - Correspondence, mostly with Scott Meredith (Scott Meredith Literary Agency, Inc.), New York, 1978. (Box-folder 74: 1)
    Includes issue of Alle Menn magazine with article on Quisling and his two women, Oslo, Norway, 1978 November
- W. George Yourieff, The Chinese (Kitaitsy). Manuscript, undated. (Folder 74: 2)
- Family correspondence, 1968-1982. (Folder 74: 3)
  Includes some photographs and negatives
- Parcel forms, receipts, 1959-1973. (Folder 74: 4)
  Includes correspondence
- Writings--Quisling book (Folder 74: 5)
  - Correspondence, notes, corrections regarding publication of Lars Torekull's three articles for Alle Kvinner magazine entitled "Alexandra Quisling,", 1975 (Folder 74: 5)
  - Copies of Vidkun Quisling's documents, diary, and letters, 1922-1931 (Folder 74: 6)
  - Copies of letters to Maria Quisling from her mother, 1930-1935. (Folder 74: 7)
    Includes shelf list for Quisling papers in the manuscript collection of the University of Oslo library
  - Correspondence between Alexandra and Maria Quisling, and Vidkun Quisling, 1923, 1932 (Folder 74: 8)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 75: 1-2)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Correspondence--General
    - 1969 (Folder 75: 3)
    - 1971 (Folder 75: 4)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Certificate of copyright registration, 1980 April 4, and correspondence with Norwegian agents regarding translation and publication agreement, 1980-1981 (Folder 75: 5)
  - Typescript of Maria Quisling's diary. Translated from Norwegian by Kirsten A. Seaver, Oslo, 1980 (Folder 75: 6)
  - Photographs of Alexandra Quisling, Maria Quisling, and Vidkun Quisling, undated (Folder 75: 7)
- Correspondence--Tsingtao, 1948-1949 (Folder 75: 8)
- Writings--Quisling book. Correspondence, 1975-1976. (Folder 75: 9)
  Includes copy of agreement on three articles written by Torekull for Alle Kvinner, between Alle Kvinner magazine (represented by Toppen Bech), reporter and U.S. correspondent Lars Torekull, and Alexandra Voronine Quisling, 1975 July
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related documents, 1969-1970 (Folder 75: 10)
- Correspondence (business and private), 1975 (Folder 75: 11)
- Typescript writing on China and the Chinese, undated (Folder 75: 12)
- Correspondence (Box 76)
  - 1956-1965 (Folder 76: 1)
  - 1961-1963 (Folder 76: 2)
  - 1970 (Folder 76: 3)
  - 1974 (Folder 76: 4)
  - 1976 (Folder 76: 5)
- Letters from Genia, 1961-1966 (Folder 76: 6)
- Photographs and negatives, undated (Box-folder 77: 1)
- Personal correspondence, 1956-1976 (Folder 77: 2)
- W. George Yourieff--Holograph, undated (Folder 77: 3)
- Writings--Quisling book. In Quisling's Shadow, first draft of introduction, 1980, 1987 (Folder 77: 4)
- Yourieff's family naturalization file, 1949 (Folder 77: 5)
- Writings--Quisling book. Copies of Alle Kvinner magazine, Oslo, Norway, 1975 (Folder 77: 6)
- Clippings on Vladimir Maiakovskii and Louis Aragon, undated (Folder 77: 7)
- Personal financial and business records, 1953-1980 (Folder 77: 8)
- Miscellany, notes, 1976, undated (Folder 77: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book. Alexandra Voronine Yourieff--Holograph, undated (Box-folder 78: 1)
- Letters from Alex and Laura, 1961-1966 (Folder 78: 2)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company, 1974-1975 (Folder 78: 3)
- Family correspondence
  - 1960-1966. (Folder 78: 4)
    Includes two pencil drawings
  - 1969-1975 (Folder 78: 5)
- One framed image of W. George Yourieff, undated (Box 79)